<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Daily R</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Daily R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 14:20:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Education, maternity leave, and breastfeeding</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-31-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 14:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-31-1/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: Statistical Modeling, Causal Inference, and Social Science</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="http://andrewgelman.com/2018/01/30/education-maternity-leave-breastfeeding/">Education, maternity leave, and breastfeeding</a></p>
        <p>&lt;p&gt;Abigail Haddad writes: In today&amp;#8217;s column, How We Are Ruining America, David Brooks writes that “Upper-middle-class moms have the means and the maternity leaves to breast-feed their babies at much higher rates than high school-educated moms, and for much longer periods.” He&amp;#8217;s correct about college grads being more likely to have access to maternity leave, [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://andrewgelman.com/2018/01/30/education-maternity-leave-breastfeeding/&#34;&gt;E</p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postdoc opening on subgroup analysis and risk-benefit analysis at Merck pharmaceuticals research lab</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-31-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 01:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-31-2/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: Statistical Modeling, Causal Inference, and Social Science</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="http://andrewgelman.com/2018/01/29/postdoc-opening-subgroup-analysis-risk-benefit-analysis-merck-pharmaceuticals-research-lab/">Postdoc opening on subgroup analysis and risk-benefit analysis at Merck pharmaceuticals research lab</a></p>
        <p>&lt;p&gt;Richard Baumgartner writes: We are looking for a strong postdoctoral fellow for a very interesting cutting edge project. The project requires expertise in statistical modeling and machine learning. Here is the official job ad. We are looking for candidates that are strong both analytically and computationally (excellent coding skills). In the project, we are interested [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://andrewgelman.com/2018/01/29/postdoc-opening-subgroup-analysis-risk-b</p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ian Lyttle is the Most Serious Conference Attendee I&#39;ve Met</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-31-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-31-5/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: Homepage on Yihui Xie | 谢益辉</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="https://yihui.name/en/2018/01/ian-lyttle/">Ian Lyttle is the Most Serious Conference Attendee I&#39;ve Met</a></p>
        <p>
        &lt;p&gt;I think I got to know Ian Lyttle in early 2014 (about 1.5 years before I left Iowa). Out of nowhere, he started to show up at the weekly ISU graphics working group meetings (led by my PhD advisors Di and Heike) after driving for three boring hours from another city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over these years, he become more and more active in the R community, and started to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ijlyttle&#34;&gt;write more R packages&lt;/a&gt; and attend more conferences. One special thing I have noticed abo</p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It is Hard to Imagine the Limit of Bureaucracy</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-31-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-31-6/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: Homepage on Yihui Xie | 谢益辉</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="https://yihui.name/en/2018/01/limit-of-bureaucracy/">It is Hard to Imagine the Limit of Bureaucracy</a></p>
        <p>
        &lt;p&gt;Among all problems in life, I hate those caused purely by some people&amp;rsquo;s personal preferences most. Personal preferences are usually fine, but you should not push them too far to block other people&amp;rsquo;s ways. For example, if you run a journal, you &lt;a href=&#34;https://yihui.name/en/2017/12/formatting-papers/&#34;&gt;should not&lt;/a&gt; force your authors to format their papers just to meet your own aesthetic standards. If you run a homeowner association, you should not force homeowners to us</p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anything that Can Look Like Cats will Look Like Cats</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-31-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-31-3/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: Homepage on Yihui Xie | 谢益辉</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="https://yihui.name/en/2018/01/looks-like-cats/">Anything that Can Look Like Cats will Look Like Cats</a></p>
        <p>
        &lt;p&gt;Tom Elliott posted a calendar plot of bus delay times &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tomelliottnz/status/958455527524130817&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. My first reaction was, these little area graphs look like cats! Five seconds later, I saw
Luis A. Apiolaza&amp;rsquo;s reply: They look like cats! All of a sudden, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murphy%27s_law&#34;&gt;Murphy&amp;rsquo;s Law&lt;/a&gt; came to my mind, and I have got Yihui&amp;rsquo;s Cats-looking Law. For the record, the full text of the law is:&lt;/p</p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Properly Write a URL</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-31-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2018-01-31-4/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: Homepage on Yihui Xie | 谢益辉</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="https://yihui.name/en/2018/01/valid-url/">How to Properly Write a URL</a></p>
        <p>
        &lt;p&gt;My two least favorite parts to write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34;&gt;the &lt;strong&gt;blogdown&lt;/strong&gt; book&lt;/a&gt; were: the chapter on Hugo (Chapter 2), and the appendices (B and C) on some basic knowledge about web technologies. I found it quite challenging to describe the full pictures, and some technical details can be frustrating for me to introduce. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a simple example in this post: how to write a valid URL (or link).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think it is dead sim</p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily R</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>
        <p>Source: R Bloggers</p>
        <p>Link: <a href="https://yufree.github.io/daily/">Daily R</a></p>
        <p> </p>
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>